# SHIBAA ADHIKARI

## React Developer

Kathmandu, Nepal • +977 9818246881 • shibaaadhikari0@gmail.com

in @ www.linkedin.com/in/shibaaadhikarii

Frontend developer with 1.5 years of experience, excelling in crafting intuitive user interfaces through strong proficiency in frontend technologies and a keen eye for design. Proven track record of effective collaboration and clear communication in fast-paced development environments.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Software Engineer Trainee

Baneshwor, Kathmandu

Optimum Futurist

Mar, 2023 - Jul, 2023

- Created a user-friendly website connecting people with nearby service pros like plumbers and electricians for easy access to local help.
- Applied Scrum methodologies to effectively manage tasks and prioritize work items.
- Delivered weekly presentations on topics related to software development to enhance team knowledge and skills.
- Created apps using React, Node, and Postgres SQL.

Frontend Developer

Crupee Software Development Pvt.ltd

Baluwatar, Kathmandu Mar, 2022 - Mar, 2023

- Developed static official websites for Crupee Software.
- Collaborated with a team of 7 members on the design and implementation of Restaurant Management Admin System.
- Incorporated research findings into actionable strategies for improved business performance.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelors of Computer Application**

Boudha, Kathmandu

 $Xavier\ International\ College$ 

Nov, 2019 - Present

## **PROJECTS**

#### Gharko Kaam

- Contributed to the "My Favorites" feature by implementing Redux components.
- Collaborated with the design lead to integrate the Report Abuse page design using Reactstrap.
- Developed and implemented Nepali to English translation features.

https://gharkokaam.com/

## Crupee Software Development Pvt. Ltd. Website

- Collaborated with a team of developers and worked under the supervision of a senior developer to develop a website using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Utilized Git for version control and project management.
- Contributed to the design and implementation of the website's user interface.

https://crupeesoft.com/

## Music Streaming Web Applications

- $\bullet \quad Implemented \ user \ authentication \ features \ such \ as \ login \ and \ signup \ using \ JWT \ tokens.$
- Developed API endpoints for login, signup, adding favorites, creating playlists, and fetching songs using Node.js.
- Utilized Reactstrap framework for creating a responsive and visually appealing user interface.
- Designed and implemented seamless user interactions for the specified features using the React JavaScript library.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### Best Permorfer of the month

In July 2023, I was recognized as the Best performer of the month while collaborating with a team of six members at Optimum Futurist.

## TRAINING/CERTIFICATIONS

## **AWS Academy Cloud Foundations**

2023

AWS User Group Nepal

Hosted by AWS User Group Nepal to empower female participants

## Xavier Science, IT & Business Expo

2023

 $Xavier\ International\ College$ 

Participated in IT Expo showcasing projects, including Food Share Nepal.

## **AWARDS**

## Winner of Xavier DIgital Expo

Boudha, Nepal

Xavier International College 2021

Presenting on the topic "Covid-19 update Database"

## **SKILLS**

React, Node.js, Redux, Reacstrap, Tailwind Css, PostgreSQL

#### REFERENCES

Sagar Khanal - Team Lead Samrat Neupane - Software Engineer

Optimum Futurist Remote Coach +977 9846643732 9860558853

sagarrkhanal@gmail.com sammyken90@gmail.com